Finding aid to the Elizabeth Pafford papers CA.MS.01158
Smith College Archives
Elizabeth Pafford papers
1926-1987
Smith College Archives
Pafford, Elizabeth
CA.MS.01158
1.333 linear feet (4 containers)
Elizabeth Pafford was a 1930's Smith College graduate and was very active in her Connecticut community. Her collection contains material on her time at Smith, including biographical materials, photographs, correspondence, Travel Logs, and coursework.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Pafford was born in Brooklyn, New York, to Dr. Frederic and Helen Adams Pafford on May 24, 1910. In 1927, Pafford graduated from Packer Collegiate Institute in Brooklyn and entered Smith College. She received her bachelor's degree from Smith in 1931. On January 5, 1935, she married Robert P. Anderson, a young lawyer. They moved to Noank, Connecticut, where she raised their two sons, Robert and Frederic Anderson, and a foster daughter, Cynthia Lewis Borden. Pafford was active in the Noank community and in her Baptist Church. In the church, Pafford was chairman of the music committee, served on the building committee, was a member of the church choir, and was the church's deacon, becoming honorary deacon in 1981. Pafford also served on the Board of Trustees of both Connecticut and Mitchell Colleges and for Mystic-Noank Library. She was dedicated to conservation and was active in the Mystic Garden Club and the Pequotsepos Nature Center. She was a member of Connecticut Children's Aid Society, Special Gifts chairwoman for United Way of Southeastern Connecticut, and a volunteer driver for the Transportation Answering Service. In 1971, Pafford received the Mystic Chamber of Commerce's 11th Annual Community Service Award. She died in 1987.
Scope and Contents
The Elizabeth Pafford Papers contain correspondence, class notes, memorabilia, travel logs, photographs, and poems. The collection is primarily related to Pafford's years as a Smith student, including a trip she took to Europe in the summer of 1930. There are, however, several letters Pafford received from friends and family after graduation, including several from her Smith roommate Caroline (Cal) Woodhull, and her notes from the 1933 Alumnae College.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were donated by Mary Chrisman Anderson, Elizabeth Pafford's daughter-in-law and member of the Class of 1959. Date unknown.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Related Materials
80. Class of 1931 Records
Pafford, Elizabeth
- Class Notes, Miscellaneous, 1929, undated (Box 2034, Folder 1)
- Class Notes, Art 26, Italian Painting, undated (Box 2034, Folder 2)
- Class Notes, Art 312 Landscape Architecture (trees and shrubs), 1931 (Box 2034, Folder 3)
- Class Notes, Art 312 Landscape Architecture (annuals and perrenials), 1931 (Box 2034, Folder 4)
- Class Notes, Art 312 Landscape Architecture (special list), 1931 (Box 2034, Folder 5)
- Class Notes, Botany 11, undated (Box 2034, Folder 6)
- Class Notes, Botany 33, 1930 (Box 2034, Folder 7)
- Class Notes, Botany 34, undated (Box 2034, Folder 8)
- Class Notes, Music, 1929 (Box 2035, Folder 1)
- Class Notes, Zoology II, 1929 (Box 2035, Folder 2)
- Class Notes, Ornithology, 1929 (Box 2035, Folder 3)
- Biographical Material, 1930-1987 (Box 2035.1, Folder 1)
- Grade Cards, Academic, 1926-1931 (Box 2035.1, Folder 2)
- Alumnae College Notes, 1933 (Box 2035.1, Folder 3)
- Freshman Year Memorabilia, 1927-1928 (Box 2035.1, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1927-1976 (Box 2035.1, Folder 5)
- Songs, Poems, 1927-1931 (Box 2035.1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence to Frederic Pafford Jr, 1927-1928 (Box 2035.2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence to Frederic Pafford Sr, 1927-1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence to Jane Pafford, 1927-1928 (Box 2035.2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence to Mother, 1927-1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence to Family, 1927-1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence from Family, 1929-1978 (Box 2035.2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence from Misc. Friends, 1928-1979 (Box 2035.2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence from Caroline Woodhull, 1928-1981 (Box 2035.2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence from Caroline Woodhull, undated (Box 2035.2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence from Smith College, 1931-1984 (Box 2035.2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence from Silver Lake Camp, 1931 (Box 2035.2, Folder 11)
- Travel to Europe, General, 1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 12)
- Travel to Europe, Guidebooks, 1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 13)
- Travel to Europe, Photographs (Commercial), 1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 14)
- Travel to Europe, Postcards, 1930 (Box 2035.2, Folder 15)
- Travel Log, unidentified January-March, undated (Box 2035.2, Folder 16)